<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Intuitive Programmer</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Intuitive Programmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 09:33:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>1% more over time</title>
      <link>/posts/003-one-percent-more-over-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 09:33:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/003-one-percent-more-over-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The math is there, with sustained effort, results become apparent. I&amp;rsquo;m
using this blog to serve as a measure of my knowledge in java development.
I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that at some point this might help others on their journey. Today,
during a pairing session, I had forgotten how to kill the process that is on
a certain port. It was kind of agitating but it served as a reminder that we
should invite such an experience to be something of good use, something that
will serve to increase your understanding of a specific domain of choice
given that you are deliberate about it. Killing the process on port :8080&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;lsof -i :8080 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;this will print out the PID which you will then proceed to kill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;kill -9 PID 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This might feel awkward if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done this stuff
before, but worry not, developing an understanding of what the port is and
why you need to kill it is important and an early lesson that benefits even experienced developers to revisit.  This is a quick and simple one for today and remember, as long as you do 1% of concentrated effort, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the results in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug early and debug often</title>
      <link>/posts/002-debug-early-debug-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 09:33:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/002-debug-early-debug-often/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a new software developer, it is your responsibility to understand
the product that you are developing for and ask questions in instances where
you do not know the answer.  Having spent the better part of my career in
marketing and graphic design, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed an astute ability to listen and
ask good questions. While developing a technological understanding of the
tools is important and necessary, I found that augmenting the technical
learning with practical business domain understanding was critical in
allowing me to develop a fluency in the product that I was working with.
Between each and every goal, between each and every gap in knowledge were
small incremental steps towards understanding. Mindfully we take these steps and
enjoy the process of stepping forward with our foot grounded in our very best
understanding of the problem. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s bad engineering, and most people
reason with problems differently. I don&amp;rsquo;t know, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say exactly
what route is the best route and that&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s mostly just important to find
what works with you and to reinforce it. The debugger works for me but
admittedly even I&amp;rsquo;m questioning that tactic, and recognizing that my style will
evolve over time and that&amp;rsquo;s a process you&amp;rsquo;ve got to fall in love with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alvin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-block&#34;&gt;Code Block&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-typescript&#34; data-lang=&#34;typescript&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;) {
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;YES&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The felt experience of software development</title>
      <link>/posts/001-software-dev-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 09:33:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/001-software-dev-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software engineering has boomed. If you&amp;rsquo;re between the ages of 24 and 45,
then likely you are or know someone who is a software engineering.
Let&amp;rsquo;s remember exactly what software engineering is. The development of an idea into an actuality.
Our generation has seen such a scale of rapid development in the application development world that
anyone with an idea and knowledge of programming can potentially disrupt longstanding industries.
This is the age of the idea. The demand for software engineers is huge.
Training schools, known as boot camps, aim to upskill even the most novice of software engineers.
This drastically reduced the barrier to entry for this field. A more diverse talent pool of
applicants presented itself in a time when inequality gaps stemmed from systems
that inadvertently oppressed women and people of color. I am one of the thousand
of people who decided to pursue software engineering as a career path with little prior training
as a Fine Arts major who went into marketing and communications. I&amp;rsquo;ll share honestly and transparently.
Perhaps as a way to provide historical record of this time and place that we find ourselves in.
This blog will certainly evolve over time, and I hope to evolve with it.
I hope you do too somehow. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for being here in this space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
